Oleksii Buriatov

DevOps Engineer

LinkedIn: Oleksii Buriatov | GitHub: oburiatov | oleksii.buriatov@gmail.com | Telegram: oburiatov

EDUCATION

National Technical University of Ukraine "Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

Bachelor's Degree (graduated)

Sep 2019 - Jun 2023

121 FICT - Faculty of Informatics and Software Engineering (Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Kyivstar Kyiv, Ukraine

Big Data DevOps Engineer

Jan 2022 - present

- Migration on-premise infrastructure into Microsoft Azure
- Building CI/CD pipelines in GitLab
- Configuration system settings with Ansible
- Deploying services using Helm charts and Kubernetes
- Configuration peering between different resource groups and VPN gateways
- Using IaC (Terraform) for describing infrastructure
- Monitoring cloud infrastructure with Prometheus + Grafana + ELK stack in Azure Kubernetes Service
- Administration Big Data tools (such as NiFi, Kafka, Hadoop, Spark clusters)
- Database administration (Postgres, Apache Hive, Greenplum)
- Deploying API using VirtualServer in Kubernetes + Keycloak

Kyivstar Kyiv, Ukraine

DevOps Engineer (Internship)

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

- Managing on-premise infrastructure (linux installation, replacing disks, disk partitioning)
- Writing Bash/Python scripts for infrastructure configuration
- Set up monitoring with Prometheus + Grafana + ELK
- Building custom images and deploying containers into Docker
- Set up deployments in Kubernetes
- Revision on-premise security infrastructure (such as connectivity and opened ports between different private networks)

SKILLS

Hard skills Linux administration, MS Azure, Bash/Python scripting, automation with

ansible (AWX), Gitlab, CI/CD, Docker/Kubernetes usage, set up monitoring

system (Prometheus, Grafana, ELK), Jira/Confluence

Soft skills Selflearning, diligence, team working, proactive

Languages Ukrainian - Native, English - Intermediate

ABOUT ME

I am a DevOps Engineer, working in Big Data. I'm experienced in building CI/CD pipelines, building and configuring docker containers, managing Kubernetes. I have administrative experience of Big Data instruments, such as Apache NiFi, Kafka, Hadoop, ELK stack. The basis of knowledge is Linux administrative skills.

I'll be so glad to get acquainted with you.